Let's get this one!
Look, Ioryogi! Such a cute kitty!
I can no longer care for him.
Please take him home with you.
Don't you go causing trouble for people again!
He's so soft!
You're not even listening to me!
I can't leave the kitty all by himself!
Then what are you gonna do?
This!
Now the kitty won't be lonely anymore and I can help find someone to take care of him!
Do you plan on living here for the rest of your life?!
Kobato.
How do I do this again?
The simplest things in life
end up being the most difficult.
I just want to smile when I'm happy
and sing a song whenever I please.
I was told, "Someday, your dream will come true."
But when exactly will that be?
I can't wait that long!
I spread my arms
on the count of one two three
and gather all the light in the world.
Tell me,
isn't there something I can do?
Even if someone hurts my feelings,
I'll keep running toward the light.
Even if I trip, fall, and cry my eyes out, I still believe.
Although it may seem silly...
I believe in tomorrow.
Production
The Kobato Protection Group
...The Kitten's Lullaby.
A person who can't even look after herself plans on taking care of a cat. Ridiculous!
But I couldn't just leave him there like that...
Now you're taking in abandoned cats?
No! It's just that the owner can't take care of him anymore.
Same thing.
If you don't have the resolve to see it all the way through, don't get involved.
Bully.
Good advice, doncha think?
Kitty?
What's the matter?
He's probably hungry.
Arithmetic
Hanamaro
Drill
I did
it!
So much
fun!
Chiho.
What's the answer to number five?
Oh no, you don't know either?
Coming!
It's Kobato!
Hello!
I'm hungry!
Mama's out right now.
We only have these.
But too many sweets will...
Huh?
I mean! It's not for me!
It's for the kitty.
So cute!
The owner can't take care of him anymore,
and I was just wondering if there was anything I could get to feed him with.
Shh!
Is it okay if we go to your room, Kobato?
Yes.
It looks like he likes it.
Thank goodness.
Um... Why are you two talking so quietly?
Having pets in this apartment is prohibited.
Someone living here before had a dog and the neighbors complained that he was too noisy.
So Mama won't take tenants with pets anymore.
I guess I can't keep him here.
Do you think you could bring him back to his owner?
I don't know.
The kitty was just in a box by himself and I didn't see the owner's name anywhere.
I see.
But sooner or later, the kitty will homeless again!
It'd be nice if we could find someone who would take him in...
I'll go to Yomogi Nursery and ask Miss Sayaka tomorrow!
I'm sure Miss Sayaka would say yes!
And if he's at Yomogi Nursery, we could go visit him any time!
Then we need to pick a name for him!
Kobato, did you have anything in mind?
Me?
I can't just think of something on the spot!
How about Milk since he's all white?
And he seems to love milk too!
Milk? What a cute name! That's wonderful!
Yomogi
Nursery
So cute!
His fur's completely white!
She said his name is Milk.
Milk! Here kitty!
I wanna hold him too!
Me too!
Lemme pet him!
Looks like everyone likes him.
Then it would be okay for him to...
Achoo! Achoo!
Yuzuru!
Come here for a second.
Are you okay?
Yuzuru, you're allergic to cats, aren't you?
Allergic... to cats?
It's means you get rashes or sneeze,
or even worse, get an asthma attack when you come in contact with cats.
Miss Sayaka, keeping a cat at the nursery is impossible.
I guess so.
I'm sorry, Kobato.
Your thoughtlessness causes trouble for the people around you.
I'm not thoughtless!
Then can you take responsibility yourself?
Fujimoto!
If you're just showing that you care about him for your own self-satisfaction,
then you're the same as the owner who abandoned him.
I'm sorry, Kobato.
I'm okay, really.
No, I'm sorry.
Stop it!
Don't tickle me! I might look like a stuffed animal, but I'm not one!
Kobato? So this is where you were hiding.
Miss Sayaka?
Do you mind if I sit next to you?
Yes.
I'm sorry to disappoint you.
No, no, I'm sorry as well.
Fujimoto didn't mean any harm either.
I think he might've been projecting himself onto that kitten...
No, it's nothing.
I'll look for someone to take in the kitten too.
I'm sure we'll be able to find someone!
Right!
Well, what're you gonna do now?
I'm going to look for someone to take care of Milk!
I can't continue causing trouble for everyone!
Agreed.
You're causing me trouble too.
Miss Sayaka! Hello!
Is Milk here?
Allergic to cats?
Yes. I'm sorry about this.
No, it's okay.
Maybe we should ask Mama after all.
We can't! Pets are prohibited, remember?
If we ask, we'll cause problems for her.
You're right...
Is there anyone who would be willing to take care of this kitty?
Please become this kitty's owner!
Please take care of this-
Kobato!
Chiho! Chise!
Milk! Here kitty.
Were you a good kitty?
I'm sorry. I asked Miss Sayaka, but...
We just came from the Nursery.
It's not your fault, Kobato.
But I still haven't found anyone to take him in.
We'll help you look!
We'll definitely find someone for you, Milk!
I'm sorry, I've already got my hands full taking care of all of the children...
Oh no, Catherine, what's the matter?
Kobato, we should go!
Right! Excuse us!
You persistent salesman!
Milk!
Domoto!
Kobato?
Milk! Here kitty!
Wow, so cute!
Someone to take in that kitten?
Yes.
I live by myself so I can't think of anyone off the top of my head, but I'll ask around too.
Thank you so much.
I feel like I'm causing trouble for everyone...
I don't think of it as trouble at all.
You're working so hard; it just makes us want to help you.
Oh, that's...
It might be a good idea to stop going around knocking on strangers' doors though.
But Fujimoto said
that if you're just showing that you care about him for your own self-satisfaction,
then you're the same as the owner who abandoned him.
Typical Fujimoto for you.
You can't let him get you down.
I don't think anyone would want to abandon such a cute kitty.
There must've been some sort of circumstance...
But when Fujimoto said that... he seemed really lonely.
But what he said was right. I can't do things half-heartedly!
I need to do my best at everything I can!
I'll go try knocking on the doors of the people I know this time.
All right. If anything comes up, here's my cell phone number. Give me a call, okay?
Okay! Thank you!
Kudo
Doesn't look like anyone's home.
European Style Sweets   Tirol
They're closed today...
We deal with food products in the store, so keeping a cat's a little difficult.
I see...
I'm sorry I can't help you out.
Hello? This is Mihara.
Sayaka? A kitten?
I wish I could keep him here, but...
Those children are working so hard too...
I understand. See you.
Oh?
It's gotten pretty dark out now, hasn't it.
Milk looks pretty worn out too.
Milk?
He's hungry, isn't he?
One, two...
Three!
I can't do anything... how shameful.
You can't even buy food for him!
I know!
Hey, Chise?
What?
I think we should go ask Mama after all.
I'm sure she would let us keep him. And then we can sleep with Milk tonight!
Yes, let's!
Kobato, you should stay with us too!
Okay!
The lady from...
If it isn't the beautiful songstress.
Kobato, you know her?
Yes!
How is the baby?
His mother is looking after him today because she has today off from work.
That's nice.
But why are you here?
I heard that a young lady was trying to find a kitten a new home.
It's this darling, isn't it?
He's so little and adorable.
If it's all right with you, I wonder if I could take him home with me.
Really?
Of course. I only have one grandchild,
so it'd be wonderful if this kitten could become his playmate.
But...
There are people who sneeze and cough when they come in contact with cats.
Will the baby be okay?
The pizza deliveryman was worried about the same thing.
Pizza deliveryman?
He was going around asking everyone if they'd be willing to take in a kitten.
That's why I came over here.
It was Fujimoto.
My grandson loves animals.
He isn't allergic to cats either.
There, there.
Isn't that great, Milk?
You won't be alone anymore!
I'll be going then.
Bye bye, Milk!
We'll come visit you!
Grandma, wait!
This is food for Milk.
Thank you. I'll be sure to use it.
Please take care of Milk.
Please!
The room somehow feels bigger now that Milk isn't here anymore.
What a relief!
Milk's milk bowl.
I'm sure Chiho and Chise feel the same way.
Where are you going?
Kobato?
Good evening!
Um...
If you're looking for Chiho and Chise, they're on the roof.
I wonder if Milk's happy at his new home.
I'm sure he is. That grandma seemed really nice...
I'm sure Milk is in good hands!
Kobato?
Oh, the-
I forgot to return this to you.
Milk's milk bowl...
Yes.
That's right... The night I met that grandma, there was a full moon just like there is tonight.
There were beautiful cherry blossoms in bloom.
The baby that she took out on a walk with her just wouldn't stop crying.
I tried to comfort him too, but...
I just made him cry harder!
And then?
What happened?
And then... I sang a song for him.
You sang, Kobato?
Yes. And then the baby stopped crying.
What kind of song was it?
Um...
I want to hear it!
Me too!
Sing for us, Kobato?
Please?
All right.
The flowers that bloom in the spring
and the endless sky of summertime
are both brilliantly engraved into my heart.
Even when it rains and the windows are closed,
This song...
the overflowing light from my heart shines from above the clouds.
Guide me, O voice, so far, far away.
Like smiles...
Like songs...
The resonating sound of the wind.
Happiness or sadness,
I'll embrace all of it and continue walking forward.
They're what make my hands...
...strongly connect to yours.
What do you want?
Thank you for helping Milk!
He has a very good owner now thanks to you.
Is that all you have to say?
Yes!
What are you doing?!
I remembered something important...
May I please borrow your phone?
Well, if you hear of anyone who likes cats let me know, ok?
Thanks.
Kiyokazu Fujimoto
Kiyokazu?
Hello?
Ah... um...
Kobato?
What's up?
We were able to find someone to take in the kitty!
I just wanted to let you know...
Is that so.
Yes! Fujimoto found someone for us.
Kiyokazu did?
I see.
I'm sorry for bothering you with all of this.
No, don't be. I'm glad.
See you.
There are more of them.
But how come?
Fujimoto found a new owner for Milk... I wasn't able to do anything.
You weren't able to help anyone, were you?
You caused huge problems for everyone by bringing that cat home!
Yes... I caused so many people problems and worry!
It's give-and-take. That's how the world works.
You noticed how upset Chiho and Chise were about having to give up the cat,
and you sang for them.
I only wanted to tell them about the baby and his grandma...
And it's that desire that allowed you to reassure them.
People's hearts can also be healed by song, can't they?
But...
Because of the wound on my ear...
Zero points, Kobato!
Ehh?!
But you know... It's so round, it looks just like the full moon tonight!
That isn't something to be happy about!!
Speaking of perfect circles, Milk's milk bowl is also round like the moon.
We all match!
Fine! If you like perfect circles so much,
then you'll get a perfect zero on every assignment from here on!
That's so mean, Ioryogi!
Even though we all want to fly,
we're being deceived by gravity.
In reality, everybody can already fly.
The reason why that child looks so sad
might be because she left her shadow somewhere.
If so...
If telling you "Thank you",
or hearing "Thank you" just makes you smile,
then doing those things will make me happy.
And they'll make you happy too.
Don't worry, we're together.
It's mysterious as to why tears roll down
even though I'm happy.
Next
...A Summer Memory.